# PHILIP KOUCHNER

## **Professional Summary**

In 2014, I took the first step towards my career as a web developer by entering the school of Computer Science in Holon Institute of Technology (HIT) in Israel. Three years later I received my B.Sc. diploma. Seeking to broaden my knowledge, I took a "Full Stack Web Developer" class at UC Berkeley Extension and I am a fresh graduate (September 2020) with a 4.0 GPA. Enthusiastic Junior Full Stack Web developer eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, excellent organizational skills, creativity & innovation. Clear understanding of Front-End and Back-End technologies.

Phone: 050-6526838 | Email: philipk179@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/philip-kouchner-886264100/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/PhilipK-webdev">https://github.com/PhilipK-webdev</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://philipkouchner.com/">https://philipkouchner.com/</a>

#### Education

- Boot camp Certificate: University of California, Berkeley-Berkeley, CA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express & React and also learned through behavior skills: Communication, Organization, Prioritization & Team work.
- Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, 08/2017
   Holon Institute of Technology Israel
  - · GPA: 81
  - · **Projects and Courses** in C#, C++ and Java.
  - · Data Structure and Algorithms.
  - · Network TCP/Router/IP/Server/HTTP/UDP/Wireshark.
  - · Cybersecurity Encryption/ Injection Attack/ Digital Certificate/Input Validation

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front-End: HTML, CSS, JS, React Back-End: Node.js, express, NPM.

UI/Framework: ¡Query, Bootstrap, Material - UI

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL.

Hosting/Deploying: Github, Heroku.

Concepts: Git, MVC, RESTful API, JavaScript(ES6+), AJAX, Axios, Jira, Zeplin.

#### **Work History**

### Intern as a Software developer at Playdigo Inc. 01/2021 to 07/2021 – Israel

Developing scalable and modern components using Material-UI as a framework, CSS, HTML5 and modern JavaScript (ES6) using both react version (react hooks and react class components). Collaborate with team members using Git commands. Working with Agile methodology. Succeeded to be on time with very tight deadlines, by being efficient and prioritize my assignments.

### Administration and Information Technology Technical Support, 12/2017 to 06/2021

#### Consulate General of Israel - San Francisco, CA

Representing Israel's interest and serving as a liaison to the Information Technology Support in the Pacific North West. Delivered onsite technical support 3x a week, resolving technical issues and maintaining a stable work environment. Collaborated with vendors outside my company to locate and resolve advanced problems by collaborating together to ensure reliable operation of the company.

#### **PROJECTS**

### StockTracker | GitHub Link | Live Link |

- Full-stack web application using several APIs to provide and help users to understand when and what company to invest by getting information on market trends.
- Developed a SQL database populated by the user.
- Developed for server-side web application logic, integration and authentication using Passport.
- Manage git repository, team workflow, and branch integration.
- HTML, CSS, Materialize, Ajax, Moment.js, Passport, chart.js

## Mern Health Tracker | GitHub Link | Live Link

- MERN Health Tracker is a full-stack web application designed for tracking calorie intake. You can search for
  food items and add logs to your profile, keeping track of what you've eaten, along with a detailed breakdown
  of the nutritional content of those foods.
- Developed UI/UX ,attach pages using react-router-dom and developed components using ReactJS . Axios calls to make the integration between the server and the front-end.
- Manipulating DOM by using React hooks (useState ,useHistory, useEffect).
- ReactJS, CSS, Node.js, mySQL, Sequelize, express, express-session, jwt, rechart.js

### **Military Service:**

Released with dignity as a Platoon Sergeant from Combat Engineering Corps 2007-2010.

#### **Additional Skills**

- Team player and friendly.
- Resourceful, motivated and organized.
- Strong passion for learning, and ability to adapt to new technologies.
- Experience in speaking in front of groups.
- Ability to multi-task

Languages: Hebrew (mother tongue), English (fluent), Russian(mother tongue)